I don't know about you,
it's just too hot today, isn't it?
오늘도 무척 더웠지만
And it's going to get even worse.
Temperatures in the mid-30s Celsius...
내일은 더 덥겠습니다
기온이 더 올라서
...that's the mid-90s Fahrenheit,
tomorrow, maybe even hitting 100.
37도까지
치솟을 거라는군요
So, please, remember to cover up
and stay cool...
그럼 저희 방송을
들으면서
...with the hottest hits on your FM dial.
시원한 저녁 시간
보내세요
Come on, guys, time to go home.
얘들아, 집에 가자
Come on, love, off you get.
어서 내려
- Do we have to?
- Yes, we do.
- 가야 돼?
- 그래
I'll make you your favorite dinner
to compensate.
대신 저녁 맛있는 거
해줄게
He squealed like a pig, didn't he?
돼지처럼 꽤꽥대더라
Yeah, brilliant punch, Big D.
Did you see his face?
환상적인 펀치였어
그 자식 얼굴 봤냐?
Hey, Big D.
빅 D
Beat up another 10-year-old?
또 꼬마 때렸어?
- This one deserved it.
- Yeah.
맞을 짓 했거든
- Five against one, very brave.
- Well, you're one to talk.
- 5 대 1로? 참 용감하네
- 너보단 낫지
Moaning in your sleep every night?
At least I'm not afraid of my pillow.
난 베개가 무섭다고
밤마다 울진 않거든
"Don't kill Cedric."
케드릭을 죽이지 마
Who's Cedric, your boyfriend?
그게 누군데?
네 애인이냐?
- Shut up.
- "He's going to kill me, Mum."
- 닥쳐!
- 날 죽이려고 해, 엄마!
Where is your mum?
엄마 어딨는데?
Where is your mum, Potter?
엄마 어딨어, 포터?
She dead?
죽었어?
Is she dead?
Is she a dead Pott...?
죽었냐구, 포터
- Dudley.
- Dudley, let's go.
- What's going on?
- What are you doing?
- 뭐야?
- 어쩐 거야?
- I'm not doing anything.
- We're getting out of here, Dudley.
내가 그런 게 아냐!
Come on, Dudley, hurry up.
Dudley, run.
두들리, 도망쳐!
Expecto Patronum.
익스펙토 패트로눔!
Mrs. Figg.
피그 할머니!
Don't put away your wand, Harry.
지팡이 아직 치우지 마라
They might come back.
다시 올지도 몰라
Dementors in Little Whinging,
whatever next?
리틀 위닝에
디멘터가 나타나다니
- Whole world's gone topsy-turvy.
- I don't understand. How do you know...?
- 세상이 미쳐 버렸어
- 할머니가 어떻게…
Dumbledore asked me
to keep an eye on you.
덤블도어가
널 지켜봐 달랬다
Dumbledore asked you?
You know Dumbledore?
덤블도어?
교수님을 알아요?
After You-Know-Who
killed that poor Diggory boy last year...
작년에 '그 사람'이
케드릭을 죽였는데
...did you expect him to let you
go wandering on your own?
널 혼자 돌아다니게
놔뒀겠니?
Good Lord, boy.
They told me you were intelligent.
똑똑하다 들었는데,
하는 소리였군
Now, get inside and stay there.
집에 꼼짝 말고 있어
Expect someone will be in touch soon.
Whatever happens, don't leave the house.
누군가 찾아올 거다
절대 밖엔 나오지 마
It is hot. That's right, hot everywhere.
There's sweat. There's stifling.
Diddykins?
우리 아들?
Is that you?
너니?
Duddy. Vernon, come quick.
여보, 빨리 와 봐요
We're going to have to
take him to a hospital.
병원에 데려가야 돼요
Who did this to you, boy?
누가 이랬어?
Happy, are we, now?
이제 속이 후련하냐?
You've finally done it.
You've finally driven him loopy.
우리 귀한 아들을
바보로 만들어 놨잖아
Vernon, don't say that.
말조심해요!
Well, just look at him, Petunia.
Our boy has gone yumpy.
보라구, 페투니아
이게 바보 아님 뭐야?
I've reached my limit, do you hear?
더는 못 참아
This is the last I'm gonna take
of you and your nonsense.
네놈이고 마법이고
전부 징글징글해!
- Dear Mr. Potter.
- What?
친애하는 포터 군
The Ministry has received intelligence
that at 6:23 this evening...
마법부는 오늘 저녁 6시 23분에
귀하가 머글이 보는 앞에서
...you performed the Patronus Charm
in the presence of a Muggle.
패트로누스 마법을
사용했다는 정보를 입수했습니다
As a clear violation...
이는 명백한
미성년 마법사의
...of the Decree for the Reasonable
Restriction of Underage Sorcery...
행동 제한 법령에
위배되므로
...you are hereby expelled...
귀하를 호그와트 마법 학교에서
...from Hogwarts School
of Witchcraft and Wizardry.
퇴학 조치합니다
Hoping you are well, Mafalda Hopkirk.
건강하길 바랍니다
마팔다 홉커크
Justice.
정의는 살아 있어
He's not very well.
Sorry, Hedwig.
미안해
Very clean, these Muggles.
너무 깔끔해
- Tonks, for God's sake.
- Unnatural.
- 통스, 제발 좀!
- 비정상이야
Professor Moody.
무디 교수님
- What are you doing here?
- Rescuing you, of course.
- 어떻게 오셨어요?
- 널 구해 주러 왔지
But where are we going?
The letter said I've been expelled.
어디 가는 거죠?
전 퇴학당했어요
You haven't been. Not yet.
Kingsley, you take point.
아직은 아냐
킹슬리, 선두에 서
But the letter said...
편지엔…
Dumbledore persuaded the minister
to suspend your expulsion...
덤블도어가
장관님께 청문회를
...pending a formal hearing.
- A hearing?
- 요청하셨다
- 청문회요?
Don't worry. We'll explain everything
when we get back to headquarters.
본부로 돌아가서
전부 설명해 줄게
Not here, Nymphadora.
여기선 안돼, 님파도라
Don't call me Nymphadora.
님파도라라고
부르지 말아요!
Stay in formation, everyone.
Don't break ranks if one of us is killed.
대형 유지해, 누가 죽더라도
이탈해선 안 돼
Come on, you, around the corner.
Come on.
빨리 와
In you go, son.
들어가자
There've been no sightings.
No deaths. No proof.
He almost killed Harry.
If that isn't proof enough...
해리를 죽일 뻔했잖소
Yes, but guarding you-know-what
is the most important...
현재로선 그걸 지키는 게
가장 중요해요
We must trust Dumbledore on this.
덤블도어를 믿어 봅시다
Was he able to protect Harry last year?
Tonight I say it's time to take action.
작년 일 벌써 잊었소?
행동에 나설 때요
Cornelius Fudge is a politician first
and a wizard second.
장관은 마법사 일보단
권력 유지가 우선이니
- His instinct would be to ignore it...
- Keep your voices down.
- 그가 돌아온 걸 부인할 겁니다
- 목소리 낮춰요
He's getting stronger and stronger
by the minute. We have to act now.
그가 점점 강해져요
지금 움직여야 돼요
- Harry.
- Mrs. Weasley.
- 해리
- 위즐리 아줌마
Heavens, you're all right.
무사해서 다행이다
Bit peaky, but I'm afraid dinner will wait
until after the meeting's finished.
야위었구나, 저녁은 좀 기다리렴
회의가 안 끝났거든
Nope. No time to explain.
Straight upstairs, first door on the left.
설명할 시간 없다
올라가렴, 왼쪽 첫째 방이야
Yeah.
Mudblood, werewolves,
traitors, thieves.
머글 태생, 늑대인간
배신자, 도둑놈들이
If my poor mistress
knew the scum they let into her house...
집에 들어와 있는 걸
주인마님이 아셨다면
...what would she say to old Kreacher?
이 크리처한테
뭐라 하실까?
Oh, the shame.
수치스러운 일이야
- Freaks.
- There, there, mistress.
- 쓰레기들!
- 노여움 푸세요, 마님
Scum of the earth.
Not like it was in the days of my fathers.
옛날 같았으면
상상도 못 할 일이야
Kreacher is here.
압니다요
Oh, Harry.
해리!
Are you all right? We overheard them
talking about the Dementor attack.
괜찮은 거야?
디멘터 공격을 받았다면서?
- You must tell us everything.
- Let the man breathe, Hermione.
- 전부 말해 봐
- 숨 좀 돌리게 해줘
And this hearing at the Ministry.
It's just outrageous.
마법부 청문회라니?
말도 안 돼
I've looked it up.
They simply can't expel you.
퇴학은 못 시킬 거야
- It's completely unfair.
- Yeah.
너무 불공평해
There's a lot of that
going round at the moment.
불공평한 게
한두 가지가 아냐
So, what is this place?
여긴 어디야?
- It's headquarters.
- Of the Order of the Phoenix.
- 본부야
- 불사조 기사단 본부
It's a secret society.
덤블도어 교수님이
Dumbledore formed it back when
they fought You-Know-Who.
'그 사람'과 처음 싸울 때
만든 비밀 조직이야
Couldn't have put any of this
in a letter, I suppose?
왜 편지 안 보냈어?
I've gone all summer
without a scrap of news.
방학 내내
아무것도 몰랐잖아
We wanted to write, mate.
Really, we did.
편지 쓰고 싶었어
진짜야
- Only...
- Only what?
- 근데…
- 뭐?
Only Dumbledore made us swear
not to tell you anything.
덤블도어가 네겐
비밀로 하랬어
Dumbledore said that?
교수님이?
But why would he keep me in the dark?
Maybe I could help.
왜 나한테 숨겨?
내가 도울 수 있잖아
I'm the one
who saw Voldemort return...
볼드모트와 싸웠고
...the one who fought him,
who saw Cedric Diggory get killed.
그가 케드릭을
죽이는 것도 봤어
- Harry.
- Thought we heard your dulcet tones.
- 해리
- 네 목소리 같더라
- Don't bottle it up, though. Let it out.
- If you're all done shouting...
- 참지 마, 소리 질러
- 다 질렀으면
Do you wanna hear something
a little more interesting?
재밌는 얘기
들으러 갈까?
If anyone has a right to know, it's Harry.
If it wasn't for Harry...
해리도 알아야 돼요
그가 돌아온 것도
...we wouldn't even know
Voldemort was back.
걔 덕분에 알았잖소
He's not a child, Molly.
애가 아녜요
But he's not an adult either.
어른도 아니죠
- He's not James, Sirius.
- Well, he's not your son.
- 아빠하곤 달라요
- 당신 아들도 아니잖소
He's as good as.
아들이나 다름없죠
- Who else has he got?
- Hey, Ginny.
걘 혼자잖아요?
- He's got me.
- How touchingly paternal, Black.
- 내가 있잖소!
- 눈물 나겠군, 블랙
Perhaps Potter will grow up
to be a felon, just like his godfather.
녀석도 자네처럼
범죄자가 될 거야
Now, you stay out of this, Snivellus.
당신은 빠져
- Snape's part of the Order?
- Git.
- 스네이프도 기사단이야?
- 재수 없어
- About your supposed reformation.
- I know better.
- So why don't you tell him?
- Get off it.
- Quick.
안돼, 그러지 마
- Get it up.
- Crookshanks.
크룩생크!
- Stop it.
- Get off, you bloody cat.
- 그냥 둬
- 놔둬, 못된 고양이!
- Crookshanks. Leave it alone.
- Get it up.
크룩생크! 건들지 마!
- Hermione, I hate your cat.
- Bad Crookshanks.
- 망할 고양이
- 못됐어 정말!
Well, we'll be eating
down in the kitchen.
저녁은 주방에서 먹자
Just because you're allowed
to use magic now...
마법 쓸 수 있는
나이 됐다고
...does not mean you have to
whip your wands out for everything.
아무 데서나
지팡이 휘두르지 마!
Hi, Mum.
You hungry, Harry?
배고프니, 해리?
You sure you're all right, Harry?
Gave us quite a turn.
정말 괜찮은 거냐?
걱정 많이 했다
Harry Potter.
해리 포터
Sirius.
시리우스!
This is very, very peculiar.
아주 드문 경우다
It seems your hearing in the Ministry
is to be before the entire Wizengamot.
위즌가모트 위원 전부
청문회에 참석한대
I don't understand. What has
the Ministry of Magic got against me?
마법부가 저한테
왜 그러는 거죠?
Show him. He'll find out soon enough.
보여 줘요
어차피 알게 돼요
거짓말하는 소년?
He's been attacking Dumbledore as well.
장관이 덤블도어도
공격하고 있어
Fudge is using all his power, including
his influence at the Daily Prophet...
'예언자 일보'를 이용해
어둠의 마왕이 돌아왔단
...to smear anyone who claims
the Dark Lord has returned.
교수의 주장을
거짓으로 몰고 있지
Why?
왜요?
He thinks Dumbledore's after his job.
자신의 자리를
노린다 생각해
No one in their right mind
could believe that...
말도 안 돼요
제정신인 사람이면…
Exactly the point.
Fudge isn't in his right mind.
퍼지 장관은
제정신이 아냐
It's been twisted and warped by fear.
겁에 질려선 이성을 잃고
Now, fear makes people
do terrible things, Harry.
해괴한 짓을 하고 있어
The last time
Voldemort gained power...
볼드모트는 옛날에
...he almost destroyed
everything we hold most dear.
우리한테 소중한 걸
전부 다 파괴했었다
Now he's returned, and I'm afraid
the minister will do almost anything...
그런 무서운 자가
돌아왔단 사실을
...to avoid facing that terrifying truth.
어떻게 해서든
부정하려는 거지
We think Voldemort
wants to build up his army again.
볼드모트가 다시
군대를 모으고 있어
Fourteen years ago,
he had huge numbers at his command.
14년 전엔
그의 추종자가 넘쳐 났다
And not just witches and wizards,
but all manner of dark creatures.
마법사들뿐 아니라
어둠의 생물들까지
He's been recruiting heavily, and we've
been attempting to do the same.
우리도 그에 맞설 조직을
만들어 왔고
But gathering followers
isn't the only thing he's interested in.
허나, 그자 관심사가
군대뿐만은 아냐
We believe...
우리 생각엔…
...Voldemort may be after something.
다른 걸 노리고 있어
Sirius.
시리우스
Something he didn't have last time.
지난번엔 손에
넣지 못했던 걸
You mean like a weapon?
무기 같은 거예요?
No. That's enough. He's just a boy.
이제 그만해요
아직 애라구요
You say more and you might as well
induct him into the Order.
자꾸 그럼 기사단에
들어오려 할 거예요
Good. I want to join. If Voldemort's
raising an army, then I want to fight.
들어갈래요, 저도
볼드모트와 싸우겠어요!
Harry.
해리
You are hereby expelled.
퇴학 조치합니다
Before the entire Wizengamot.
청문회가 소집됐다
Trains. Underground.
땅속에 기차라니!
Ingenious, these Muggles.
머글들은 꽤나 독창적이야
Here we are.
여기다
I've never used the visitors' entrance
before. Should be fun.
방문객 입구는
나도 처음이야, 재밌겠어
Right. Good.
I'll just get my Muggle money.
좋아, 머글 돈 넣을게
Terrible. Lost a lot of Galleons
trading on the potions market.
마법의 약 거래로
엄청 손해 봤어
Daily Prophet, ladies and gentlemen.
Anybody for Daily Prophet?
'예언자 일보' 사세요!
Dumbledore: Is he daft,
or is he dangerous?
덤블도어: 위험한 마법사?
- Morning, Arthur.
- Morning, Bob.
- 좋은 아침, 아서
- 밥
Interdepartmental memos.
결재 서류들이야
We used to use owls.
Mess was unbelievable.
부엉일 썼었는데
너무 지저분해서
Merlin's beard. Thank you, Kingsley.
마법사 맙소사!
고맙네, 킹슬리
They've changed the time
of your hearing.
청문회 시간이 변경됐어
언제예요?
When is it?
In five minutes.
5분 후!
Department of Mysteries.
미스터리 부서입니다
And I'm confident, minister,
that you will do the right thing.
현명한 결정을
내리시리라 믿습니다
Yes, but we must be...
물론이오, 허나…
Remember, during the hearing,
speak only when you're spoken to.
위원들이 물어보는
질문에만 대답하고
Keep calm.
You've done nothing wrong.
침착해라
넌 잘못한 게 없어
As the Muggles say, truth will out.
머글들 말처럼,
진실은 승리한다
Yes?
알았지?
I'm not allowed in, I'm afraid.
난 못 들어가
Good luck, Harry.
행운을 빈다
Disciplinary hearing
of the 12th of August...
8월 12일
징계 청문회입니다
...into offenses committed
by Harry James Potter...
징계 대상자는
해리 제임스 포터
...resident at Number 4 Privet Drive,
Little Whinging, Surrey.
거주지는 서리 리틀 위닝
프리벳 가 4번지
Interrogators: Cornelius Oswald Fudge,
Minister of Mag...
심문인은
퍼지 마법부 장관…
Witness for the defense.
피고 측 대변인이오!
Albus Percival Wulfric...
알버스 퍼시발 울프릭
...Brian Dumbledore.
브라이언 덤블도어
You got our message
that the time and place of the hearing...
청문회 시간과 장소가
변경됐단 전갈
...had been changed, did you?
- I must have missed it.
- 받았지요?
- 못 받았소
But by a happy mistake, I arrived
at the Ministry three hours early.
허나, 우연히도
3시간 일찍 왔지요
The charges?
혐의가 뭐죠?
The charges against the accused
are as follows:
피고의 혐의는
명백히 불법인 걸
"That he did knowingly...
알고 있으면서도
...and in full awareness
of the illegality of his actions...
머글이 보는 앞에서
...produce a Patronus Charm...
패트로누스 마법을
...in the presence of a Muggle."
사용한 것이오
- Do you deny producing said Patronus?
- No, but...
- 혐의를 부인하는가?
- 아뇨
And you were aware that you were
forbidden to use magic outside school...
17세 이하는
학교 밖에서 마법 사용이
...while under the age of 17?
- Yes, I was, but...
- 금지라는 걸 알고 있었지?
- 네, 하지만…
Witches and wizards
of the Wizengamot...
존경하는 위즌가모트
위원 여러분…
I was only doing it
because of the Dementors.
디멘터 때문이었어요!
Dementors?
디멘터?
In Little Whinging?
리틀 위닝에?
That's quite clever.
그럴듯하지만
Muggles can't see Dementors,
can they, boy?
머글들은
디멘터를 보지 못해
- Highly convenient.
- I'm not lying.
- 거짓말 마
- 거짓말 아녜요!
- There were two of them, if I hadn't...
- Enough.
- 둘이었는데…
- 그만!
I'm sorry to interrupt what I'm sure
would be a very well-rehearsed story...
징계를 피하기 위해
꾸며낸 게 뻔하지만
...but since you can produce
no witnesses of the event...
네 주장을 뒷받침할
증인이 없으니…
Pardon me, minister,
but as it happens, we can.
잠깐만요, 장관님
증인이 있습니다
Please describe the attack.
당시 상황을 설명해 보세요
What did they look like?
어떻게 생겼죠?
Well, one of them was very large
and the other rather skinny.
하난 덩치가 크고
또 하난 말랐어요
Not the boys. The Dementors.
아이들 말고
디멘터 말이오
Oh, right, right. Well, big.
아, 그렇군요
커다랗고
Cloaked. Then everything went cold...
망토 걸쳤고…
그들이 나타나자
주위가 싸늘해졌어요
...as though all the happiness
had gone from the world.
세상의 모든 행복이
사라진 것처럼요
Now, look here. Dementors don't just
wander into a Muggle suburb...
디멘터가 머글들이 사는 곳을
돌아다니다 마법사와
...and happen across a wizard.
The odds are astronomical.
마주칠 확률은
제로에 가깝소
I don't think anyone would believe...
그게 우연이라고
...the Dementors were there
by coincidence, minister.
믿을 사람은 없을 겁니다
I'm sure I must have misunderstood you,
professor.
제가 잘못 알아들었겠지만
Dementors are, after all, under
the control of the Ministry of Magic.
디멘터들은
마법부 통제를 받고 있는데
And it's so silly of me, but it sounded
for a moment as though...
마치 마법부가
디멘터를 보내, 저 아이를
...you were suggesting that the Ministry
had ordered the attack on this boy.
공격하게 했단 것처럼
들리는군요
That would be disturbing indeed,
Madam Undersecretary...
놀라셨을 줄 압니다
차관님
...which is why I'm sure the Ministry
will be mounting a full-scale inquiry...
그러니, 왜 디멘터들이
아즈카반을 벗어나
...into why the two Dementors
were so very far from Azkaban...
허가 없는 공격을
감행했는지
...and why they mounted an attack
without authorization.
철저한 진상 조사가
실시돼야만 합니다
Of course, there is someone...
배후로 의심되는
...who might be behind the attack.
사람은 있지만요
Cornelius, I implore you to see reason.
장관님, 이성적으로
생각하십시오
The evidence that the Dark Lord
has returned is incontrovertible.
어둠의 마왕이
돌아왔다는 건 명백합니다
He is not back.
그는 돌아오지 않았소!
In the matter of Harry Potter...
해리 포터 경우처럼
...the law clearly states...
목숨이 위협받는 상황에선
...that magic may be used before
Muggles in life-threatening situations.
머글 앞에서 마법을 써도
불법이 아닙니다
Laws can be changed if necessary,
Dumbledore.
법은 상황에 따라
바뀔 수 있는 거요
Clearly. Has it become practice
to hold a full criminal trial...
언제부터 미성년자의
마법 사용 문제로
...to deal with a simple matter
of underage magic?
형사 재판을 열었습니까?
Those in favor of conviction?
유죄라 생각하는 분?
Those in favor
of clearing the accused of all charges?
피고가 무죄라고
생각하시는 분?
Cleared of all charges.
무죄를 판결합니다
Professor.
교수님!
Padfoot. Are you barking mad?
패드풋!
계속 짖어 댈 거요?
You'll blow the entire operation.
그러다 들키겠소!
Sirius, what are you doing here?
If somebody sees you...
시리우스, 누가 보면
어쩌려구요?
I had to see you off, didn't I?
작별 인사는 해야지
What's life without a little risk?
모험 없는 인생이
무슨 재미냐?
I don't wanna see you
get chucked back in Azkaban.
잡힐까 봐 그러죠
Don't worry about me.
내 걱정은 마라
Anyway, I wanted you to have this.
어쨌거나 이걸 주고 싶었다
Original Order of the Phoenix.
불사조 기사단
창립 단원들이야
Marlene McKinnon.
마를렌느 맥키논
She was killed
two weeks after this was taken.
이 사진 찍고
2주 후에 살해됐어
Voldemort wiped out her entire family.
볼드모트가
가족을 몰살했지
Frank and Alice Longbottom.
롱바텀 부부
Neville's parents.
네빌 부모님?
They suffered a fate worse than death,
you ask me.
죽음보다 끔찍한
고통을 겪었단다
It's been 14 years.
14년이 지났지만
And still a day doesn't go by
I don't miss your dad.
단 하루도 네 아버질
생각 않은 적 없었어
Do you really think
there's going to be a war, Sirius?
정말 전쟁이 일어날까요?
It feels like it did before.
전쟁은 벌써 시작된 거야
You keep it.
가져
Anyway, I suppose
you're the young ones now.
이젠 젊은 세대가
나설 때야
I'll see you at the train.
Bye-bye, darling.
I love you.
Hold my hand, lovey.
There they are.
They're in the far carriage.
Bye.
I'm surprised the Ministry's
still letting you walk around free.
포터,
운 좋게 풀려났지만
Better enjoy it while you can.
너무 좋아하진 마
I expect there's a cell in Azkaban
with your name on it.
머잖아 아즈카반
죄수 신세 될 테니까!
- What'd I tell you? Complete nutter.
- Just stay away from me!
- 내가 뭐랬어? 미쳤다니까
- 저리 꺼져!
It's only Malfoy.
말포이잖아
What'd you expect?
뭘 기대했어?
Hi, guys.
안녕
- Hey, Neville.
- Hey there, Neville.
안녕, 네빌
What is it?
뭐지?
- What's what?
- That. Pulling the carriage.
- 뭐가?
- 마차 끄는 짐승
Nothing's pulling the carriage, Harry.
아무것도 없어
It's pulling itself, like always.
혼자 움직이는 마차잖아
You're not going mad.
넌 미친 게 아냐
I can see them too.
나도 보이는걸
You're just as sane as I am.
넌 나처럼 정상이야
Everyone, this is Loony Love...
얜 정신병자…
Luna Lovegood.
루나 러브굿이야
What an interesting necklace.
특이한 목걸이네
It's a charm, actually.
부적이야
Keeps away the Nargles.
나글스를 쫓아 줘
Hungry.
배고프다
I hope there's pudding.
푸딩 먹고 싶어
- What's a Nargle?
- No idea.
- 나글스가 뭐야?
- 모르겠어
Good evening, children.
학생 여러분
Now, we have two changes
in staffing this year.
올해는 선생님 두 분이
새로 오셨습니다
We're pleased to welcome back
Professor Grubbly-Plank...
그루블리 프랭크
교수님…
...who'll be taking
Care of Magical Creatures...
신비한 동물 돌보기
담당이며
...while Professor Hagrid
is on temporary leave.
잠시 우리 곁을 떠난
해그리드 대신입니다
We also wish to welcome our new
Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher...
어둠의 마법 방어술 선생님도
새로 오셨어요
...Professor Dolores Umbridge.
돌로레스 엄브릿지
교수님
And I'm sure you'll all join me
in wishing the professor good luck.
새로 오신 선생님들께
행운을 빌어드립시다
Now, as usual, our caretaker, Mr. Filch,
has asked me to remind you...
학교 관리인 필치 씨가
또 신신당부를…
She was at my hearing.
She works for Fudge.
청문회에서 봤어
장관 밑에서 일해
Thank you, headmaster,
for those kind words of welcome.
따뜻한 환영의 말씀
정말 감사합니다
And how lovely to see all your bright...
날 보며 미소 짓는
여러분들의
...happy faces smiling up at me.
행복한 얼굴을 보니
참 기쁘군요
I'm sure we're all going
to be very good friends.
앞으로 좋은 친구처럼
친하게 지내길 바라요
- That's likely.
퍽이나!
The Ministry of Magic
has always considered...
마법부는 옛날부터
...the education of young witches
and wizards to be of vital importance.
어린 마법사들의 교육을
가장 중요하게 여겨왔어요
Although each headmaster...
호그와트의
역대 교장 선생님들이
...has brought something new
to this historic school...
학교를 위해
새로운 걸 도입하셨지만
...progress for the sake of progress
must be discouraged.
변화를 위한 변화는
지양돼야만 합니다
Let us preserve
what must be preserved...
보존해야 할 것은 보존하고
...perfect what can be perfected...
다듬어야 할 것은 다듬으며
...and prune practices
that ought to be prohibited.
금지돼야 할 행위는
싹을 잘라내야 하죠
Thank you, Professor Umbridge.
That really was most illuminating.
감사합니다, 교수님
유익한 연설이었어요
- Illuminating? What a load of waffle.
- What's it mean?
- 유익해? 완전 헛소리구만!
- 무슨 뜻일까?
Magic is forbidden in the corridors...
It means the Ministry's
interfering at Hogwarts.
마법부가 학교 일에
간섭하겠단 뜻이지
플로터?
Dean, Seamus.
딘, 시무스
- Good holiday?
- All right.
- 방학 잘 보냈어?
- 그럼
Better than Seamus', anyway.
시무스보다는!
Me mum didn't want me
to come back this year.
엄마가 학교를
1년 쉬라잖아
- Why not?
- Let me see. Because of you.
- 왜?
- 왜긴, 너 때문이지
The Daily Prophet's been saying a lot
of things about you and Dumbledore.
'예언자 일보'에 네 기사가 났잖아
교장 선생님 기사도
What, your mum believes them?
그걸 믿으셔?
Nobody was there
the night Cedric died.
케드릭 죽는 걸
본 사람 없잖아
I guess you should read the Prophet,
then, like your stupid mother.
그렇담 너도 멍청한 엄마처럼
거짓 기사나 읽어
- Don't talk about my mother.
- I'll have a go at anyone calling me a liar.
- 엄마 욕하지 마!
- 난 거짓말쟁이가 아냐!
- What's going on?
- He's mad, is what's going on.
- 무슨 일이야?
- 괜히 성질내잖아
Do you believe the rubbish he's
come out with about You-Know-Who?
'그 사람'에 대한
해리 얘길 믿어?
Yeah. I do.
그래, 믿어
Has anyone else
got a problem with Harry?
누구 또 해리한테
문제 있어?
- You all right?
- Fine.
- 괜찮아?
- 그래
Seamus was bang out of order, mate.
시무스가 원래
헛소리 잘하잖아
- But he'll come through, you'll see.
- I said, I'm fine, Ron.
- 신경 쓰지 마
- 난 괜찮다니까!
Right. I'll just leave you
to your thoughts, then.
그래, 귀찮게 안 할게
Harry.
해리
Bring it over here. Over here.
Oh, go on, Seamus. Go on, get it.
시무스, 잡아 봐!
Good morning, children.
좋은 아침이에요
Ordinary Wizarding Level examinations.
표준 마법사 수준 시험
O-W-Ls.
약자로 하면
O.W.L.
More commonly known as OWLs.
'OWL'이라고
더 잘 알려져 있죠
Study hard and you will be rewarded.
열심히 공부하면
보상을 받겠지만
Fail to do so,
and the consequences may be severe.
그렇지 않음 결과가
아주 끔찍할 거예요
Your previous instruction in this subject
has been disturbingly uneven.
지금까진 수업이
얼렁뚱땅 진행됐더군요
But you'll be pleased to know,
from now on...
하지만 걱정 말아요
앞으로는
...you will be following a carefully
structured, Ministry-approved...
체계적으로 이뤄진
마법부 인증 방어술
...course of defensive magic. Yes?
교육 과정을
따를 거예요, 네?
There's nothing in here
about using defensive spells?
방어법 주문은
빠져 있는데요?
Using spells?
그게 왜 필요하죠?
Well, I can't imagine why you would
need to use spells in my classroom.
교실에선 주문 쓸 일이
없을 텐데
We're not gonna use magic?
마법을 안 써요?
You'll be learning about defensive spells
in a secure, risk-free way.
안전하고 위험하지 않은
방법으로 배울 거예요
What use is that?
If we're attacked, it won't be risk-free.
공격받아도 못 쓰면
의미가 없잖아요
Students will raise their hands
when they speak in my class.
질문 있는 학생은
손을 들어요!
It is the view of the Ministry...
마법부의 입장은
...that a theoretical knowledge
will be sufficient...
여러분들이
이론만 잘 익혀도
...to get you through
your examinations...
시험을 통과하는 데
...which, after all,
is what school is all about.
아무런 문제가
없다는 거예요
And how's theory supposed
to prepare us for what's out there?
적과 싸우려면
이론만으론 부족해요
There is nothing out there, dear.
적은 없어요
Who do you imagine
wants to attack children like yourself?
해리 같은 애들을
누가 공격하겠어요?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe Lord Voldemort.
글쎄요, 볼드모트 경?
Now, let me make this quite plain.
분명히 말해 둘게요
You have been told...
어둠의 마법사가
...that a certain dark wizard
is at large once again.
다시 나타났다는
소문이 떠돌지만
- This is a lie.
- It's not a lie. I saw him. I fought him.
- 그건 새빨간 거짓말이에요
- 거짓말이 아녜요! 제가 싸웠다구요!
Detention, Mr. Potter.
끝나고 남아요
포터 군!
Cedric Diggory dropped dead
of his own accord?
케드릭이 혼자
죽었단 말이에요?
Cedric Diggory's death
was a tragic accident.
그 학생의 죽음은
비극적인 사고였어요
It was murder. Voldemort killed him.
볼드모트가
죽인 거예요!
Enough!
그만!
Enough.
그만해요
See me later, Mr. Potter. My office.
포터 군, 수업 끝나고
내 방으로 와요
Come in.
들어와요
Good evening, Mr. Potter.
어서 와, 포터
Sit.
앉아
You're going to be doing some lines
for me today, Mr. Potter.
선생님한테 대든 벌로
베껴쓰기를 해
No, not with your quill.
아니, 그거 말고
Going to be using
a rather special one of mine.
내가 준비한
특별한 깃펜으로
Now...
...I want you to write,
"I must not tell lies."
이렇게 써
"난 거짓말을 하지 않겠습니다"
How many times?
몇 번요?
Well, let's say for as long as it takes
for the message to sink in.
진심으로 잘못을
뉘우칠 때까지!
You haven't given me any ink.
잉크 안 주셨어요
Oh, you won't need any ink.
필요 없을 거야
다신 거짓말 않겠습니다
Yes?
뭐지?
- Nothing.
- That's right.
- 아녜요
- 그래
Because you know, deep down...
입이 10개라도
할 말이 없겠지
...you deserve to be punished.
벌 받을 짓 했으니까
Don't you, Mr. Potter?
안 그래?
Go on.
계속 써
- Skiving Snackboxes.
- Sweets that make you ill.
- 꾀병용 과자 세트!
- 먹으면 아파져
Get out of class whenever you like.
땡땡이에 딱이지
Obtain hours of pleasure
from unprofitable boredom.
따분한 교실에서
해방시켜 줄 거야
Care for another?
더 먹을래?
- I'm not asking you to write all of it.
- Please.
다 써 달란 게 아냐
I've been busy studying
for these stupid OWL exams.
OWL 공부하느라
시간이 없었어
I'll do the introduction. That's all.
그럼 서론만 써 줄게
Hermione, you're honestly the most
wonderful person I've ever met.
헤르미온느,
역시 네가 최고야
- And if I'm ever rude to you again...
- I'll know you've gone back to normal.
- 내가 또 못되게 굴면…
- 원래 못됐잖아
What's wrong with your hand?
손이 왜 그래?
Nothing.
괜찮은데
The other hand.
다른 손!
- You've got to tell Dumbledore.
- No.
- 덤블도어한테 말해
- 안돼
Dumbledore's got enough
on his mind right now.
나 말고도
걱정거리 많으셔
I don't want to give
Umbridge the satisfaction.
엄브릿지한테
지기도 싫고!
Bloody hell, Harry.
The woman's torturing you.
그 선생님
너한테 너무 심해
- If the parents knew about this...
- I haven't got any of those, have I, Ron?
- 부모님이 알면…
- 난 고아잖아, 론
Harry, you've got to report this.
교장 선생님께 말해
- It's perfectly simple. You're being...
- No, it's not.
- 그럼 간단히 해결돼
- 아니
Hermione, whatever this is,
it's not simple.
네 생각처럼
간단한 문제가 아냐
You don't understand.
넌 이해 못 해
Then help us to.
그럼 이해시켜 봐!
Dear Padfoot...
패드풋
...I hope you're all right.
잘 지내시죠?
It's starting to get colder here.
Winter is definitely on the way.
점점 추워지는 게
겨울이 느껴져요
In spite of being back at Hogwarts,
I feel more alone than ever.
호그와트에 돌아왔어도
너무 외로워요
I know you, of all people,
will understand.
왜 그런지
아실 거라고 믿어요
Hello, Harry Potter.
안녕, 해리 포터
- Your feet. Aren't they cold?
- Bit.
- 맨발이잖아, 안 추워?
- 조금
Unfortunately, all my shoes
have mysteriously disappeared.
신발이 전부
감쪽같이 사라졌어
I suspect Nargles are behind it.
나글스가 숨겨 놨을 거야
- What are they?
- They're called Thestrals.
- 뭐지?
- 세스트랄이야
They're quite gentle, really, but people
avoid them because they're a bit...
온순한 동물인데
사람들이 멀리해, 왜냐면…
Different.
달라서군
But why can't the others see them?
왜 딴 사람들한텐
안 보이지?
They can only be seen
by people who've seen death.
죽음을 본 사람들
눈에만 보이거든
So you've known someone
who's died, then?
너도 누가 죽는 걸 봤어?
My mum.
우리 엄마
She was quite an extraordinary witch,
but she did like to experiment...
훌륭한 마녀셨어
실험을 좋아하셨는데
...and one day,
one of her spells went badly wrong.
새 마법을 만들다
사고를 당하셨어
- I was 9.
- I'm sorry.
- 내가 9살 때
- 안됐구나
Yes, it was rather horrible.
정말 끔찍했지
I do feel very sad about it sometimes,
but I've got Dad.
생각하면 슬프지만
나한텐 아빠가 있어
We both believe you, by the way.
아빠랑 난 널 믿어
That He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named
is back, and you fought him...
네가 돌아온 '이름을 불러서는
안 될 그 사람'과 싸웠고
...and the Ministry and the Prophet
are conspiring against you.
마법부는 진실을
감추려 한다는 걸
Thanks. It seems you're about
the only ones that do.
고마워, 믿어 주는 사람은
너뿐인 것 같아
I don't think that's true.
그렇지 않아
But I suppose
that's how he wants you to feel.
그는 네가 그렇게
느끼길 원하겠지만
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이야?
Well, if I were You-Know-Who...
내가 '그 사람'이라도
...I'd want you to feel cut off
from everyone else...
네가 혼자인 것처럼
느끼게 만들 거야
...because if it's just you alone...
상대가 너 하나라야
...you're not as much of a threat.
위협이 안 될 테니까
- Do you ever stop eating?
- What? I'm hungry.
- 어쩜 그렇게 끊임없이 먹니?
- 배고픈 걸 어떡해
Harry.
해리
Can I join you?
앉아도 돼?
Pardon me, professor,
but what exactly are you insinuating?
맥고나걸 교수님,
그게 무슨 뜻이죠?
I am merely requesting
that when it comes to my students...
내가 맡고 있는
학생들한테
...you conform to the prescribed
disciplinary practices.
기존의 체벌 규정을
지켜 달란 거예요
So silly of me, but it sounds...
지금 그러니까
...as if you're questioning my authority
in my own classroom...
학생들이 어떻게 하든
그냥 놔두라는
...Minerva.
말씀인가요?
Not at all, Dolores,
merely your medieval methods.
그게 아니라 벌이 너무
가혹하다는 거예요
I am sorry, dear.
외람된 말이지만
But to question my practices
is to question the Ministry...
절 비난하는 건
마법부와 장관님을
...and by extension,
the minister himself.
비난하는 것과
다를 게 없어요
I am a tolerant woman...
어떤 경우에도
...but the one thing
I will not stand for is disloyalty.
권위에 대한 도전은
참지 않겠어요
Disloyalty.
도전요?
Things at Hogwarts
are far worse than I feared.
학교가 생각보다
훨씬 형편없군요
Cornelius will want
to take immediate action.
장관님께서 즉각
조치를 취할 겁니다
교육 법령 제23조
돌로레스 엄브릿지를
장학사로 임명한다
마법부,
교육 개혁 방안 모색
What's happened to Dumbledore?
덤블도어는 어떻게 됐죠?
Having already revolutionized...
어둠의 마법 방어술 수업을
...the teaching
of Defense Against the Dark Arts...
혁신적으로 체계화했고…
...Dolores Umbridge will,
as high inquisitor, have powers...
돌로레스 엄브릿지 교수는
장학사로서, 갈수록 악화되는
...to address the seriously falling
standards at Hogwarts School.
호그와트 마법 학교 교육의 질을
개선할 것입니다
Just one question, dear.
하나만 물을게요
You've been in this post
how long, exactly?
이 수업 맡은 지
얼마나 됐죠?
You applied first for the Defense Against
the Dark Arts post, is that correct?
원래는 어둠의 마법 방어술
교수직에 지원하셨죠?
Yes.
그렇소
But you were unsuccessful?
하지만 탈락했구요?
Obviously.
보면 알잖소
음악을 절대 금한다
위즐리 형제
발명품 사용 금지
언제 어디서나
단정한 복장 준수
Could you please predict something
for me?
나와 관련된
예언 하나 해볼래요?
I'm sorry?
네?
Move those mouths.
입 크게 벌리고!
One teensy little prophecy?
아주 간단한 예언 하나만?
Pity.
한심해
No, wait. Wait, no.
I think I do see something.
잠깐만, 잠깐만요
뭔가 보여요
Yes, I do. Something dark.
아주 사악해요
You are in grave danger.
교수님은 큰 위험에
빠질 거예요
Lovely.
그렇군요
Cho. What's going on?
초, 무슨 일이야?
It's Professor Trelawney.
트릴로니 교수님!
Sixteen years I've lived
and taught here.
여기서 16년을 가르쳤어요
Hogwarts is my home.
호그와트는 제 집이라구요
You can't do this.
이럴 순 없어요
Actually, I can.
난 할 수 있죠
- 전 정말…
- 진정해요
Something you'd like to say?
할 말 있으세요?
Oh, there are several things
I would like to say.
하고 싶은 말이야
아주 많죠
There...
그만 울어요
Professor McGonagall, might I ask you
to escort Sybil back inside?
맥고나걸 교수님,
트릴로니 교수를 안으로 모셔 주겠소?
Sybil, dear. This way.
들어가요
Thank you.
정말 고마워요
Dumbledore, may I remind you
that under the terms...
교장 선생님, 교육 법령
제23조를 잊으셨어요?
...of Educational Decree Number 23,
as enacted by the minister...
마법부 장관님께서
날 장학사로…
You have the right
to dismiss my teachers.
당신은 선생님들을
해고할 수 있지만
You do not, however, have the authority
to banish them from the grounds.
호그와트 교정에서
쫓아내는 건
That power remains
with the headmaster.
교장인 내 고유 권한이오
For now.
지금은요!
Don't you all have studying to do?
모두 들어가서
공부하도록!
Professor.
교수님?
Professor?
Professor Dumbledore. Professor!
덤블도어 교수님?
교수님!
Professor Dumbledore.
덤블도어 교수님!
That foul, evil, old gargoyle.
사악한 늙은 마녀!
We're not learning
how to defend ourselves.
방어술을 배우긴커녕
We're not learning
how to pass our OWLs.
시험도 통과 못 하겠어
She's taking over the entire school.
학교를 쥐고 흔들잖아
Security has been and will remain
the Ministry's top priority.
보안 수준을 최상위로
유지하겠습니다
Furthermore,
we have convincing evidence...
마법부가 입수한
증거에 의하면
...that these disappearances
are the work...
일련의 행방불명
사건의 배후는
...of notorious
mass murderer Sirius Black.
악명 높은 살인자
시리우스 블랙입니다
Harry.
해리!
Sirius.
시리우스!
- What are you doing here?
- Answering your letter.
- 웬일이세요?
- 편지 보냈잖아
You said you were worried
about Umbridge. What's she doing?
엄브릿지가 걱정이라며
뭘 가르치는데?
Training you to kill half-breeds?
잡종 죽이는 법?
- She's not letting us use magic at all.
- Well, I'm not surprised.
- 마법을 못 쓰게 해요
- 놀랄 일도 아니지
The latest intelligence is that Fudge
doesn't want you trained in combat.
장관은 너희가 전투 훈련
받는 걸 원치 않거든
Combat?
전투요?
What does he think,
we're forming some sort of wizard army?
우리가 군대라도
만드는 줄 안대요?
That's exactly what he thinks.
덤블도어가
That Dumbledore is assembling
his own forces to take on the Ministry.
군대를 모아 마법부를
공격할 거라고 믿거든
He's becoming more paranoid
by the minute.
겁에 질려선
완전히 이성을 잃었지
The others wouldn't want me
telling you this, Harry...
네겐 비밀로 하랬다만
...but things aren't going at all well
with the Order.
불사조 기사단
상황이 안 좋다
Fudge is blocking the truth
at every turn...
장관이 진실을
은폐하고 있어
...and these disappearances
are just how it started before.
행방불명 사건들?
옛날하고 똑같아
Voldemort is on the move.
볼드모트가
움직이기 시작했다
Well, what can we do?
어떡하죠?
Someone's coming.
누가 온다!
I'm sorry I can't be of more help.
도움이 못 돼서
미안하구나
But for now, at least,
it looks like you're on your own.
당분간은 너 혼자
전부 알아서 해야 돼
He really is out there, isn't he?
그가 정말 돌아온 거지?
We've got to be able
to defend ourselves.
방어술을 배워야 돼
And if Umbridge refuses to teach us
how, we need someone who will.
엄브릿지가 아님
딴 사람한테라도!
Harry.
해리
This is mad.
Who'd wanna be taught by me?
미쳤어? 누가 나한테
배우려고 하겠어?
I'm a nutter, remember?
Look on the bright side: You can't be
any worse than old toad face.
좋게 생각해
늙은 두꺼비보단 네가 낫지
- Thanks, Ron.
- I'm here for you, mate.
- 고맙다, 론
- 뭘!
Who's supposed to be meeting us, then?
누가 오기로 했어?
Just a couple of people.
한 두어 명
Lovely spot.
장소 참 잘 골랐네
Thought it would be safer
off the beaten track.
인적 드문 곳이
좋을 거 같았어
Matey, come back here.
Hi.
안녕!
So you all know why we're here.
우리가 모인 건
선생님이
We need a teacher.
필요해서야
A proper teacher.
진짜 선생님
One who's had experience defending
themselves against the Dark Arts.
어둠의 마법에 맞서서
자신을 방어해 본 사람
- Why?
- 왜?
Because You-Know-Who's back,
you tosspot.
'그 사람'이 돌아왔잖아
이 맹추야!
- So he says.
- So Dumbledore says.
- 해리 말이지
- 덤블도어도 그래
So Dumbledore says because he says.
해리가 그러니까
The point is, where's the proof?
증거라도 있어?
If Potter could tell us more
about how Diggory got killed...
케드릭이 어떻게
죽었는지 말해 봐
I'm not gonna talk about Cedric, so if
that's why you're here, clear out now.
그 얘긴 안 해
그게 궁금해서 온 거면 지금 돌아가
Come on, Hermione. They're here
because they think I'm some freak.
가자, 얘들한테 나는
그저 괴짜일 뿐이야
Is it true you can produce
a Patronus Charm?
패트로누스 마법,
진짜 할 수 있어?
Yes.
그래
I've seen it.
내가 봤어
Blimey, Harry.
I didn't know you could do that.
대단한걸, 해리
And he killed a basilisk, with the sword
in Dumbledore's office.
바실리스크도 죽였잖아
덤블도어 방에 있던 칼로
It's true.
맞아
Third year, he fought off
about a hundred Dementors at once.
3학년 땐
디멘터들 물리쳤고
Last year, he really did fight off
You-Know-Who in the flesh.
작년엔 '그 사람'하고
맞서 싸웠어
Wait.
잠깐만
Look, it all sounds great
when you say it like that...
그렇게 말하니까
대단한 거 같지만
...but the truth is,
most of that was just luck.
솔직히, 운이 좋았던 거야
I didn't know what I was doing
half the time. I nearly always had help.
누군가 도와줬기에
가능했던 거고
- He's just being modest.
- No, Hermione, I'm not.
- 겸손한 거야
- 아냐, 헤르미온느
Facing this stuff in real life
is not like school.
학교 수업이랑
실전은 천지차이야
In school, if you make a mistake,
you can just try again tomorrow.
학교에선 실수하면
다시 하면 돼
But out there...
그치만 실전에선…
...when you're a second away
from being murdered...
이젠 죽었구나 하는
아찔한 순간이나
...or watching a friend die
right before your eyes...
눈앞에서 친구가
죽는 걸 보면…
You don't know what that's like.
그 기분, 너흰 몰라
You're right, Harry, we don't.
그래, 우린 몰라
That's why we need your help.
네가 도와줘
Because if we're going to have
any chance at beating...
그래야 싸워 이기지
...Voldemort...
볼드모트를!
He's really back.
정말 돌아왔구나
덤블도어의 군대
엄브릿지 몰래
Right. First we need to find
a place to practice...
...where Umbridge won't find out.
연습할 곳이 필요해
- The Shrieking Shack.
- It's too small.
- 비명을 지르는 오두막집?
- 너무 좁아
- Forbidden Forest?
- Not bloody likely.
- 금지된 숲?
- 거긴 죽어도 싫어
Harry, what happens
if Umbridge does find out?
엄브릿지한테
들키면 어쩌지?
Who cares?
알게 뭐야?
I mean, it's sort of exciting, isn't it,
breaking the rules?
정말 신나지 않아?
규칙을 어기는 게!
Who are you and what have you done
with Hermione?
너 헤르미온느 맞니?
Anyway, at least we know
one positive thing that came from today.
어쨌든, 오늘 확실히
알아낸 게 있어
What's that?
뭔데?
Cho couldn't take her eyes off you,
could she?
초가 너한테서
눈을 못 떼더라
Right. Over the next few days,
we should each come up...
연습 장소로
어디가 좋을지
...with a couple of possibilities
of places we can practice.
각자 생각 좀 해봐
We've got to make sure, wherever it is,
there's no chance she can find us.
엄브릿지가 절대
못 찾을 곳으로!
Will do, Harry.
알았어
All student organizations
are henceforth disbanded.
모든 학생 모임을 해산한다
Any student in noncompliance
will be expelled.
이에 불응하는 학생은
퇴학 조치한다
Watch where you're going,
Longbottom.
잘 보고 다녀, 네빌!
You've done it, Neville.
You found the Room of Requirement.
네가 필요의 방을
찾아냈어, 네빌
The what?
무슨 방?
It's also known as
the Come and Go Room.
다른 이름은
오고 가는 방
The Room of Requirement only appears
when a person has real need of it.
꼭 필요한 사람한테만
나타나는데
And it's always equipped
for the seeker's needs.
필요한 물건들이
전부 갖춰져 있어
So say you really needed the toilet...
만약 화장실이 필요하면?
Charming, Ronald.
But, yes, that is the general idea.
참 너답다
그래, 필요한 건 다 있어
It's brilliant. It's like Hogwarts
wants us to fight back.
완벽해, 호그와트가 우릴
도와주는 거 같아
Expelliarmus.
엑스펠리아르무스!
I'm hopeless.
난 구제불능이야
You're just flourishing your wand
too much. Try it like this. Expelliarmus.
지팡이를 너무 많이 흔들었어
이렇게 해봐, 엑스펠리아르무스!
You will please copy
the approved text four times...
모두 전체 문장을
4번씩 써요
...to ensure maximum retention.
그래야 머릿속에
쏙 들어가죠
- There will be no need to talk.
- No need to think's more like it.
- 잡담은 절대 금지예요
- 생각하지 말란 거겠지
- Expelliarmus.
- Wands away.
- 엑스펠리아르무스
- 지팡이를 치워라
Stunning is one of the most useful spells
in your arsenal.
기절 마법은
아주 쓸모가 많아
It's a wizard's bread and butter, really.
마법사한텐 필수지
So come on, then, Nigel.
Give it your best shot.
좋아, 나이젤, 한번 해봐
Stupefy!
스투페파이!
Good. Not bad at all, Nigel. Well done.
아주 잘했어, 나이젤
Don't worry. I'll go easy on you.
걱정 마, 살살 할게
Thanks, Ronald.
고마워
- Come on, Ron.
잘해, 론
- You can do it.
- Come on, Ron.
- One Sickle.
- You're on.
- 1시클 내기?
- 좋지
Stupefy.
스투페파이!
- Thank you.
- Shut up.
- 고마워
- 시끄러
I let her do that.
It's good manners, isn't it?
매너 없게 여자를
기절시킬 순 없잖아?
It was completely intentional.
일부러 져준 거야
모든 학생들은
불법 행위에 대한
조사에 응해야 한다
Up you come.
Would you like a cup of tea?
올라오렴, 차 줄까?
Now, focus on a fixed point
and try again.
눈은 한 곳을 응시해
다시 해봐
Expelliarmus.
엑스펠리아르무스!
Very good. Keep your concentration.
집중력을 유지해
Great.
A little higher.
좀 더 높이 들어
I'm okay. I'm okay.
난 괜찮아, 난 괜찮아
- Stupefy.
스투페파이!
Those wishing to join
the Inquisitorial Squad for extra credit...
조사반 활동에 참여하여
특별 점수를 따고자 하는
...may sign up
in the high inquisitor's office.
학생들은 장학사 사무실에서
신청하세요
Diminuendo.
디미누엔도!
Working hard is important, but there's
something that matters even more:
열심히 하는 것보다
더 중요한 건
Believing in yourself.
자신을 믿는 거야
- Expelliarmus.
- Levicorpus. Got it.
- 엑스펠리아르무스!
- 레비코푸스!
Think of it this way.
이렇게 생각해 봐
Every great wizard in history
has started out...
역사상 위대했던
마법사들도 전부
...as nothing more
than what we are now: Students.
처음엔 우리처럼 학생이었어
If they can do it, why not us?
그들이 해냈다면
우리도 문제없어
- Stupefy.
- Expelliarmus.
- 스투페파이!
- 엑스펠리아르무스!
Expelliarmus.
Reducto.
리덕토!
- Expelliarmus.
엑스펠리아르무스!
Expelliarmus.
Fantastic, Neville. Well done, man.
끝내줬어, 네빌
잘했어
So that's it for this lesson.
오늘이 마지막이야
Now, we're not gonna be meeting again
until after the holidays.
연휴 끝날 때까진
못 만나니까
So just keep practicing on your own
as best you can.
집에 가서도 계속 연습해
And well done, everyone.
Great, great work.
모두 정말 잘해 줬어
Well done, mate.
수고했다, 친구야
Thanks.
고마워
See you after Christmas.
연휴 잘 보내
See you in the Common Room, Harry.
휴게실에서 봐
- Thanks a lot, Harry.
- No worries.
- 고마워, 해리
- 뭘
- Thank you so much.
- Not at all. Merry Christmas.
- 메리 크리스마스!
- 수고했어
- Thank you, Harry.
- Thank you. Merry Christmas.
- 고마워
- 메리 크리스마스!
- Merry Christmas.
- Have a good Christmas.
- 메리 크리스마스
- 성탄절 잘 보내
- Have a great Christmas, Luna.
- We've been thinking.
- 너도, 루나
- 엄브릿지 차에다
We could always slip Umbridge
some Puking Pastilles.
구역질 사탕을
살짝 넣어 볼까?
Or Fever Fudge. They give you
massive, pus-filled boils...
발열 사탕이나,
효과가 직방이야
Sounds great, guys.
Would you excuse me?
재밌겠는걸? 잠깐만
Are you all right? I heard Umbridge
gave you a rough time the other day.
괜찮니? 엄브릿지가 널
못살게 군다며?
Yeah. I'm okay.
난 괜찮아
Anyway, it's worth it.
힘들지만 참아야지
It's just, learning all this...
방어술을 배우면서
궁금해졌어
...makes me wonder whether,
if he'd known it...
케드릭도 그 마법들
알았을까 하고…
Cedric did know this stuff.
케드릭도 알았어
He was really good.
실력도 대단했고
It's just, Voldemort was better.
볼드모트가 더 강했지만…
You're a really good teacher, Harry.
넌 좋은 선생님이야
I've never been able
to stun anything before.
덕분에 기절 마법을
처음 성공시켜 봤어
Mistletoe.
겨우살이야
Probably full of Nargles, though.
나글스가 우글댈 거야
What are Nargles?
그게 뭔데?
No idea.
나도 몰라
Well, how was it?
말해 봐, 어땠어?
Wet.
축축했어
I mean, she was sort of crying.
초가 울었거든
That bad at it, are you?
그렇게 못했어?
I'm sure Harry's kissing
was more than satisfactory.
해리가 키스를
못 해서가 아냐
Cho spends half her time
crying these days.
요즘 많이 울잖아
You'd think a bit of snogging
would cheer her up.
그래도 키스했음
좋아해야지
Don't you understand
how she must be feeling?
걔 기분 어떨지 모르겠어?
Well, obviously
she's feeling sad about Cedric...
해리랑 키스하면서
...and confused about liking Harry
and guilty about kissing him...
죽은 케드릭한테
죄책감 느낀 거야
...conflicted because Umbridge might
sack her mum from the Ministry...
엄브릿지 교수가
엄마 해고할까 걱정되고
...and frightened of failing her OWLs
because she's worrying about everything.
시험에 떨어질까 봐
겁도 났을 테고
One person couldn't feel all that.
They'd explode.
그걸 동시에 느꼈단
머리 터져 버릴 거야
Just because you've got
the emotional range of a teaspoon...
너처럼 무감각한 애가
뭘 알겠니!
Harry.
해리
Voldemort may be after something.
볼드모트가
노리는 건 따로 있어
Something he didn't have last time.
지난번엔 손에
못 넣었던 거지
Harry.
해리
In the dream,
were you standing next to the victim...
꿈에서 희생자 옆에
서 있었니?
...or looking down at the scene?
아님 멀리서 바라봤어?
Neither. It was like I...
둘 다 아녔어요, 제가…
Will you please just tell me
what's happening?
어떻게 된 거죠?
Everard, Arthur's on guard duty
tonight.
에버라드,
아서가 야간 보초요
Make sure he's found
by the right people.
우리 사람들이
찾아내야 돼요
- Sir.
- Phineas.
- 교수님!
- 피니어스!
You must go to your portrait
at Grimmauld Place.
기사단 본부의
초상화로 가서
Tell them that Arthur Weasley
is gravely injured...
아서 위즐리가
크게 다쳤고
...and his children will be arriving there
soon by Portkey.
아이들이 곧 그곳에
도착한다고 전해요
They've got him, Albus. It was close,
but they think he'll make it.
아서를 찾았는데
생명엔 지장 없소
What's more,
the Dark Lord failed to acquire it.
그가 노리는 물건도
안전하고
Oh, thank goodness. Next we need to...
다행이군, 다음엔…
Look at me!
절 봐요!
What's happening to me?
전 어떻게
돼 가는 거죠?
You wished to see me, headmaster?
보자고 하셨다구요?
Oh, Severus. I'm afraid we can't wait.
Not even till the morning.
스네이프, 시간이 없소
아침까지 기다렸다간
Otherwise, we'll all be vulnerable.
모두 위험해질 거요
It appears there's a connection...
너와 생각이 연결된 걸
...between the Dark Lord's mind
and your own.
어둠의 마왕도
Whether he is, as yet, aware of this
connection is, for the moment, unclear.
알고 있는지
현재로선 확실치 않다
Pray he remains ignorant.
그가 모르고 있길 기도해라
You mean, if he knows about it, then...
안다면 제 생각을
...he'll be able to read my mind?
- Read it, control it...
- 읽을 수 있단 말이에요?
- 읽고, 조종하고
...unhinge it.
미치게 만들겠지
In the past, it was often
the Dark Lord's pleasure...
옛날에도
어둠의 마왕은 종종
...to invade the minds of his victims...
피해자들 마음속에
침투해
...creating visions designed
to torture them into madness.
미치광이로 만들었다
Only after extracting the last exquisite
ounce of agony...
우린 상상도 못 할
고통을 안겨 주곤
...only when he had them literally
begging for death, would he finally...
죽여 달라고 애원하면
...kill them.
그때 죽였지
Used properly,
the power of Occlumency...
제대로만 사용하면
오클러먼시의 힘이
...will help shield you
from access or influence.
그가 침투하는 걸
막아 줄 거다
In these lessons, I will attempt
to penetrate your mind.
내가 네 마음속으로
들어가려고 할 테니까
You will attempt to resist.
어떻게 해서든 막아 봐
Prepare yourself.
준비해
Legilimens.
레질리멘스!
Concentrate, Potter. Focus.
정신을 집중해
해리, 집중해!
Ho, ho, ho. Merry Christmas.
메리 크리스마스!
Here we go.
얘들아!
Daddy's back.
아빠 돌아오셨다!
Sit down, everybody, sit down.
That's it. Now, presents.
자자, 모두 앉으렴
선물 풀어야지
- And a nice big box for Ron.
- Big box for you. And...
- 큰 상자는 론
- 정말 크네!
Fred and George. Come on, open up.
빨리 풀어 봐
- I want to see your faces.
- Yes.
어떤 표정일지 궁금해
- Try it on.
- Thanks, Mum. It's perfect.
- 입어 봐
- 맘에 쏙 들어요
- Just what he wanted, actually.
- Yeah. Right. Thanks, Mum.
- 론이 원하던 거야
- 고마워요
Come on, then, everybody.
Let's clear this away.
자, 이제 다 치우고
Oh, Harry, Harry.
해리!
There you are.
어서 오렴
- Happy Christmas.
- Thank you.
메리 크리스마스!
- Lovely to have you with us.
- Thank you.
- 잘 왔다
- 고맙습니다
Now, Daddy. Pass that to Daddy.
이건 아빠 선물
- Thank you.
- Has everybody got?
- 고마워
- 전부 풀어 봤지?
Fred? George?
- Hermione.
- A Christmas toast.
모두 건배하자
To Mr. Harry Potter...
해리가 아녔음
...without whom I would not be here.
난 오늘
여기 없었을 거다
- Harry.
해리
Harry.
That is delicious.
I shall be needing some more of that.
맛이 기가 막힌걸
더 먹어야겠어
Daddy, don't forget last Christmas.
지난 성탄절 사건 잊었수?
I can't understand
why you don't want to wear it, Ronald.
왜 입기 싫단 거야, 론?
I look like a bloody idiot, that's why.
멍청해 보이니까
No more than usual, Ron.
원래 멍청하잖아
I don't know why...
엄마의 감각을
그냥 믿으라구
Nasty brat, standing there
as bold as brass.
역겨운 꼬마 놈이
뻔뻔하게 서 있군
Harry Potter,
the boy who stopped the Dark Lord.
해리 포터,
어둠의 마왕을 막고
Friend of Mudbloods
and blood-traitors alike.
머글과 피가 섞인
잡종들의 친구
- If my poor mistress only knew...
- Kreacher!
- 불쌍한 주인마님이 아셨다면…
- 크리처!
That's enough of your bile.
Away with you!
악담 그만하고 가 봐!
Of course, master.
그럽죠, 주인님
Kreacher lives to serve
the noble house of Black.
이 크리처는 고귀한
블랙 가문의 종인걸요
Sorry about that.
미안하구나
He never was very pleasant,
even when I was a boy.
내가 어렸을 때도
심보가 고약했어
Not to me, anyway.
적어도 나한텐!
What, you grew up here?
여기서 자라셨어요?
This is my parents' house.
부모님 집인데
I offered it to Dumbledore
as headquarters for the Order.
불사조 기사단에
본부로 기증했지
About the only useful thing
I've been able to do.
내가 한 유일한
쓸모 있는 일이었어
This is the Black family tree.
우리 집안 족보다
My deranged cousin.
미쳐 버린 사촌
I hated the lot of them.
전부 끔찍이 싫었지
My parents with their pure-blood mania.
부모님은 순수 혈통
광신도셨고
My mother did that after I ran away.
내가 도망치자
어머니가 이러셨다
Charming woman.
대단한 분이셨지
I was 16.
16살 때였어
Where did you go?
어디로 가셨죠?
Round your dad's.
네 아버지한테
I was always welcome at the Potters'.
항상 날 반겨 줬어
I see him so much in you, Harry.
널 보면
네 아버지가 생각나
You are so very much alike.
쏙 빼닮았어
I'm not so sure.
잘 모르겠어요
Sirius, when I was...
시리우스, 꿈에서…
When I saw Mr. Weasley attacked,
I wasn't just watching.
아서가 공격당하는 걸
보기만 한 게 아녜요
I was the snake.
제가 뱀이었어요
And afterwards,
in Dumbledore's office...
덤블도어 교수님 방에선
...there was a moment
when I wanted to...
충동적으로…
This connection
between me and Voldemort.
저와 어둠의 마왕이
생각을 공유하는 게
What if the reason for it
is that I am becoming more like him?
제가 그자처럼
돼 가는 거라면요?
I just feel so angry all the time.
요즘은 사소한 일에도
너무 화가 나요
And what if, after everything
that I've been through...
그간 겪어 온 일들 때문에
...something's gone wrong inside me?
What if I'm becoming bad?
제가 나쁜 사람이
돼 가는 거라면요?
I want you to listen to me
very carefully, Harry.
내 말 잘 들으렴, 해리
You're not a bad person.
넌 나쁜 사람이 아냐
You're a very good person
who bad things have happened to.
착한 사람인데
나쁜 일이 생긴 거지
You understand?
이해하겠니?
Besides, the world isn't split
into good people and Death Eaters.
또, 세상은 단순히
선과 악으로 나뉘지 않아
We've all got both light and dark
inside of us.
우리한텐 빛과 어둠이
동시에 존재하고 있지
What matters
is the part we choose to act on.
어느 쪽을 택하든,
그 선택이
That's who we really are.
우리 본질을 결정해
Harry, time to go.
해리, 갈 시간이야
When all this is over,
we'll be a proper family.
이번 일이 다 끝나면
같이 살게 될 거야
You'll see.
약속하마
Come on.
Really?
진짜?
Harry. Harry.
해리! 해리!
Hagrid's back.
해그리드가 돌아왔어
I'm sorry.
미안해
I will say this one last time.
마지막으로 묻겠어요
I'm ordering you to tell me
where you've been.
어딜 갔었는지
솔직히 말해요
I told you. I've been away
for me health.
말했잖아요
건강 때문에 쉬다 왔다고!
- Your health?
- Yeah. Bit of fresh air, you know.
- 건강 때문에?
- 네, 맑은 공기 좀 쐤죠
Oh, yes. As gamekeeper,
fresh air must be difficult to come by.
이 숲엔 맑은 공기가
부족한가 보죠?
If I were you,
I shouldn't get too used to being back.
다시 돌아왔다고
좋아하지 말아요
In fact, I mightn't bother
unpacking at all.
짐도 풀지 말고!
This is top-secret, right?
절대 비밀이다, 알았지?
Dumbledore sent me
to parley with the giants.
거인들을 만나고 왔어
Giants?
거인들을?
You found them?
찾았어요?
Well, they're not that hard to find, to be
perfectly honest. They're so big, see?
찾는 건 어렵지 않았지
덩치 커서 잘 보이거든
I tried to convince them
to join the cause.
기사단 합류를
설득하러 갔는데
But I wasn't the only one
that was trying to win them over.
녀석들을 찾아간 게
나뿐만은 아녔더군
- Death Eaters?
- Yes.
- 죽음을 먹는 자들?
- 그래
Trying to persuade them
to join You-Know-Who.
'그 사람'의 편에 서라고
설득하고 있었어
- Did they?
- I gave them Dumbledore's message.
- 그래서요?
- 교수님 메시지를 전했지
Suppose some of them remember
he was friendly to them. I suppose.
옛날에 녀석들한테
잘해 주셨거든
And they did this to you?
그들이 이랬어요?
Not exactly, no.
아냐
Oh, go on, you have it, then,
you dozy dog.
옜다, 먹어라
게을러터진 녀석!
It's changing out there.
밖이 심상치 않아
Just like last time.
지난번처럼!
There's a storm coming, Harry.
폭풍이 오고 있어
We'd all best be ready when she does.
단단히 준비하고
있어야 돼
We have confirmed
that 10 high-security prisoners...
특별 감시를 받던
죄수 10명이
...in the early hours of yesterday evening
did escape.
아즈카반 감옥에서
어젯밤 탈출했으며
And of course, the Muggle prime minister
has been alerted to the danger.
머글 수상에게
위험성을 알렸습니다
We strongly suspect...
이번 집단 탈출 사건의
...that the breakout was engineered...
배후는
...by a man with personal experience
in escaping from Azkaban...
아즈카반을 탈출한
악명 높은 살인마
...notorious mass murderer Sirius Black...
시리우스 블랙으로,
이번에 탈출한
...cousin of escapee
Bellatrix Lestrange.
벨라트릭스 레스트랭의
사촌입니다
아즈카반 집단 탈출
Dumbledore warned Fudge
this could happen.
덤블도어가
경고했던 일인데
He's gonna get us all killed
just because he can't face the truth.
퍼지 장관 때문에
다 죽게 생겼어
Harry.
해리?
I wanted to apologize.
사과할게
Now even me mum says the Prophet's
version of things don't add up.
엄마도 '예언자 일보'
기사가 엉터리래
So, what I'm really trying to say
is that I believe you.
그러니까 내 말은…
이젠 널 믿어
Neville?
네빌?
Fourteen years ago...
14년 전에
...a Death Eater
named Bellatrix Lestrange...
벨라트릭스 레스트랭이란
죽음을 먹는 자가
...used a Cruciatus Curse
on my parents.
우리 부모님한테
정보를 캐내려고
She tortured them for information...
크루시아투스 저주를 썼는데
...but they never gave in.
끝까지 버티셨대
I'm quite proud to be their son.
그분들 아들인 게
자랑스러워
But I'm not sure I'm ready
for everyone to know just yet.
그치만 다른 애들한테
말해도 될지 모르겠어
We're gonna make them proud, Neville.
That's a promise.
부모님한테 자랑스러운
아들이 될 거야
Make it a powerful memory,
the happiest you can remember.
제일 행복했던 기억,
그 순간을
Allow it to fill you up.
Keep trying, Seamus.
머릿속에 떠올려 봐
계속해, 시무스
George, your turn now.
조지, 네 차례야
Expecto Patronum.
익스펙토 패트로눔!
A full-bodied Patronus
is the most difficult to produce...
실물 크기 패트로누스가
불러내기 가장 힘들지만
...but shield forms can also be equally
useful against a variety of opponents.
방어막만 만들어 내도
적을 막아낼 수 있어
Wow, that was really good.
Fantastic, Ginny.
잘했어, 지니!
Just remember, your Patronus can only
protect you for as long as you stay focused.
정신을 집중하는 게
제일 중요해
So focus, Luna.
집중해, 루나
Think of the happiest thing you can.
가장 행복했던 순간을 생각해
Expecto Patronum.
- I'm trying.
- I know. It's good.
- 노력 중이야
- 알아, 잘하고 있어
This is really advanced stuff, guys.
You're doing so well.
어려운 마법인데
모두 잘하고 있어
Expecto Patronum.
익스펙토 패트로눔!
I'll make short work of this.
내가 도와주지
Bombarda Maxima.
봄바르다 맥시마
Get them.
잡아!
Been watching them for weeks.
제가 말씀드렸죠?
And see, "Dumbledore's Army"...
덤블도어의 군대가
...proof of what I've been telling you
right from the beginning, Cornelius.
확실한 증거예요, 장관님
All your fear-mongering
about You-Know-Who...
'그 사람'이 나타났다는
...never fooled us for a minute.
헛소문을 퍼뜨려서
We saw your lies for what they were:
공포심을 유발한 건
A smokescreen for your bid
to seize control of the Ministry.
마법부를 장악하려는
연막이었던 거죠
Naturally.
맞소
No, professor.
He had nothing to do with it. It was me.
교수님은 상관없어요
제가 한 거라구요!
Most noble of you, Harry, to shield me,
but as has been pointed out...
보호해 주려는 건 고맙지만
다 들켜 버렸구나
...the parchment clearly says
"Dumbledore's Army," not "Potter's."
양피지에 적혀 있잖니
'포터'가 아니라 '덤블도어' 군대라고
I instructed Harry
to form this organization.
내가 해리한테
시킨 일이니
And I, and I alone,
am responsible for its activities.
모든 책임은 내가 지겠소
Dispatch an owl to the Daily Prophet.
'예언자 일보'에
부엉이를 보내
If we hurry, we should still make
the morning edition.
아침 신문에 기사를 내게
Dawlish, Shacklebolt,
you will escort Dumbledore...
도울리쉬, 샤클볼트
덤블도어를
...to Azkaban...
아즈카반에 데려가도록
...to await trial
for conspiracy and sedition.
음모와 선동죄로
재판에 회부하겠다
I thought we might hit this little snag.
그건 좀 어렵겠군
You seem to be laboring
under the delusion that I'm going to...
내가 반항 않고
What was the phrase?
얌전히 갈 거라고
- Come quietly.
착각하는 것 같은데
Well, I can tell you this:
분명히 말하지만
I have no intention
of going to Azkaban.
난 아즈카반에 갈 생각이
전혀 없소
Enough of this.
못 참아!
Take him.
끌고 가!
Well, you may not like him, minister...
장관님은 싫어하실지 몰라도
...but you can't deny...
위대한 마법사인 건
...Dumbledore has got style.
틀림없네요
돌로레스 엄브릿지 교수가
알버스 덤블도어를 대신하여
호그와트 마법사 학교의
교장직을 맡는다
Boys and girls are not permitted
to be within eight inches of each other.
남녀 학생들 간의 신체 접촉은
절대 금지예요
Those wishing to join
the Inquisitorial Squad for extra credit...
조사반 활동에 참여하여
특별 점수를 따고자 하는…
Students will be submitted to questioning
about suspected illicit activities.
학생들은 불법 행위에 대한
조사에 응해야 하고
Any student in noncompliance
will be expelled.
이에 불응하는 학생은
퇴학 조치하겠어요
Harry.
해리
You did everything you could.
No one could win against that old hag.
넌 최선을 다했잖아
그 할망구는 못 당해
Even Dumbledore
didn't see this coming.
덤블도어도 예상 못 했었어
Harry, if it's anyone's fault, it's ours.
따지고 보면 우리 잘못이야
Yeah, we talked you into it.
우리가 널 꼬셨잖아
Yeah, but I agreed.
난 동의했고
I tried so hard to help,
and all it's done is make things worse.
도움이 되고 싶었는데
상황만 더 악화시켰어
Anyway, that doesn't matter anymore.
이젠 상관없어
Because I don't want to play anymore.
All it does is make you care too much.
난 그만둘 거야
빠져들면 들수록
And the more you care,
the more you have to lose.
잃을 게 많아져
- So maybe it's just better to...
- To what?
- 난 이제…
- 뭐?
To go it alone.
나만 생각할래
Hagrid.
해그리드
Any idea where he's taking us?
어디로 가는 거지?
Hagrid, why can't you just tell us?
어디 가는지
말해 주면 안 돼요?
I've never seen the centaurs so riled.
켄타우로스들이
굉장히 화났어
And they're dangerous
at the best of times.
온순할 때도 위험한데!
The Ministry restricts
their territory much more...
마법부가 영역을
더 제한하면
...they'll have a full uprising
on their hands.
폭동이 일어날 거야
Hagrid, what's going on?
무슨 일이에요?
I'm sorry to be so mysterious, you three.
비밀로 한 건 미안하다만
I wouldn't be bothering you at all with it,
but with Dumbledore gone...
덤블도어 교수님도
사라지셨고
...I'll likely be getting the sack
any day now.
난 곧 해고될 테니까
And I just couldn't leave
without telling someone about him.
그전에 만나는 게
좋겠다 싶어서
Grawpy.
그롭!
Down here, you great buffoon.
아래를 봐, 이 멍청아
Grawpy.
그롭
Brought you some company.
친구들을 데려왔어
I couldn't just leave him, because...
두고 올 수가 없었어
Because he's my brother.
내 동생이거든
Blimey.
맙소사
Well, half brother, really.
아버지는 달라
He's completely harmless, just like I said.
Little high-spirited, is all.
아주 온순한 녀석이야
장난은 좀 심하지만
- Grawpy, that is not polite.
- Hagrid, do something.
- 그롭, 그러지 마!
- 말려 봐요!
We talked about this.
You do not grab, do you?
사람은 장난감이
아니라고 했지?
That's your new friend, Hermione.
네 새 친구, 헤르미온느야
Grawpy.
Grawp.
그롭!
Put me down.
날 땅에 내려놔요!
Now.
당장!
You all right?
괜찮아?
Fine.
응
Just needs a firm hand, is all.
버릇을 고쳐 줄
사람이 필요해
I think you've got an admirer.
너한테 반했나 봐
You just stay away from her, all right?
멀리 떨어져요
알았어요?
He gets his own food and all.
음식은 알아서
구해 먹는데
It's company he'll be needing
when I'm gone.
내가 떠나고 나면
친구가 필요할 거야
You will look after him, won't you?
돌봐 줄 거지?
I'm the only family he's got.
내 유일한 가족이야
Feeling sentimental?
부모님 생각하나?
- That's private.
- Not to me.
- 개인적인 기억이에요
- 나한텐 아니지
And not to the Dark Lord,
if you don't improve.
오클러먼시 못 익히면
어둠의 마왕한테도!
Every memory he has access to
is a weapon he can use against you.
그가 네 기억을
무기로 사용하면
You won't last two seconds
if he invades your mind.
넌 2초도 못 버텨
You're just like your father.
애비랑 똑같아
Lazy, arrogant.
게으르고 건방지고
- Don't say a word against my father.
- Weak.
- 아버질 모욕하지 마요!
- 나약해
- I'm not weak.
- Then prove it.
- 아녜요!
- 그럼 증명해 봐
Control your emotions.
감정을 통제하고
Discipline your mind.
정신을 단련시켜
Legilimens.
레질리멘스!
Harry.
해리
Sirius.
시리우스
I may vomit.
구역질 나는군
Stop it.
그만해요!
Is this what you call control?
감정을 통제하랬지?
We've been at it for hours.
If I could just rest.
4시간째예요
쉬고 싶다구요!
The Dark Lord isn't resting.
어둠의 마왕은 쉬지 않아!
You and Black, you're two of a kind.
너하고 블랙은
Sentimental children forever whining
about how unfair your lives have been.
삶이 불공평하다며
끊임없이 징징대지
Well, it may have escaped your notice,
but life isn't fair.
아직 모르나 본데,
삶은 원래 불공평해
Your blessed father knew that.
In fact, he frequently saw to it.
네 애비 덕분에
뼈저리게 느꼈지
- My father was a great man.
- Your father was a swine.
- 훌륭한 분이었어요!
- 비열한 인간이었어!
- Legilimens.
- Protego.
- 레질리멘스!
- 프로테고!
Come on, Moony, Padfoot.
빨리! 무니, 패드풋
Snape. Expelliarmus.
스네이프!
엑스펠리아르무스!
Nice one, James.
잘했어, 제임스
- Dad.
- Impedimenta.
- 아빠
- 임페디멘타!
Snivellus Greasy.
Right. Who wants to see me
take off Snivelly's trousers?
스네이프 바지 벗기는 거
보고 싶은 사람?
Snivellus Greasy.
Enough.
그만!
그만해
Your lessons are at an end.
오클러먼시 수업은
이걸로 끝내겠다
I...
Get out.
내 방에서 썩 나가
- What's your name?
- Michael.
- 이름이 뭐야?
- 마이클
Your hand's gonna be fine, Michael.
손은 괜찮을 거야
Yeah. It's not as bad as it seems. See?
보기만큼 끔찍하진
않다구, 봐
It's fading already.
금세 사라지는걸
You can hardly see ours anymore,
and the pain stops after a while.
잘 보이지도 않잖아
아픈 것도 잠깐이야
As I told you once before, Mr. Potter...
전에도 말했지만, 포터…
...naughty children
deserve to be punished.
나쁜 짓을 하면
벌을 받아야 돼
You know, George...
조지
...I've always felt our futures lay outside
the world of academic achievement.
우리한텐 학교가 안 맞아
Fred, I've been thinking
exactly the same thing.
전적으로 동감이야, 프레드
정숙, 5학년 시험 중
시험 과목 - 마법 이론
All right, professor!
교수님!
Here you go.
간다!
Ready when you are.
모두 준비해!
I need that prophecy.
나는 그 예언이 필요하다
You'll have to kill me.
날 죽여야 할 거야
Oh, I will.
But first, you will fetch it for me.
죽여야지
예언을 가져온 다음에!
Crucio.
크루시오!
Sirius.
시리우스야
Harry, are you sure?
확실해?
I saw it. It's just like
with Mr. Weasley.
위즐리 아저씨 때랑 똑같아
It's the door I've been dreaming about.
꿈에서 봤던 문인데
I couldn't remember
where I'd seen it before.
어딘지 기억이 안 나
Sirius said Voldemort
was after something.
볼드모트가 노리는 물건
Something he didn't have the last time,
in the Department of Mysteries.
뭔진 모르지만
미스터리 부서에 있어
Harry, please, just listen.
해리, 들어 봐
What if Voldemort
meant for you to see this?
볼드모트가 판 함정이면?
What if he's only hurting Sirius
because he's trying to get to you?
널 유인하려고 그러는 거면?
What if he is?
I'm supposed to just let him die?
그럼 시리우스가
죽게 놔두란 말이야?
Hermione,
he's the only family I've got left.
나한테 남은
유일한 가족이야
What do we do?
어떡하지?
We'll have to use the Floo Network.
플루 가루를 쓰자
Umbridge has the chimneys
under surveillance.
엄브릿지가
굴뚝들을 감시해
Not all of them.
전부는 아냐
Alohomora.
알로호모라!
Alert the Order if you can.
기사단에 알려
- Are you mental? We're going with you.
- It's too dangerous.
- 미쳤어? 우리도 갈래
- 너무 위험해
When are you going to get it
into your head? We're in this together.
아직도 몰라?
우린 한배를 탄 거야
That you are.
그래, 잘 아는군
Caught this one
trying to help the Weasley girl.
이 녀석도 한패예요
You were going to Dumbledore,
weren't you?
덤블도어한테
가려고 한 거지?
- No.
- Liar.
- 아뇨
- 거짓말!
- You sent for me, headmistress?
- Snape, yes.
- 부르셨다구요?
- 네, 스네이프
The time has come for answers, whether
he wants to give them to me or not.
해리한테
대답을 받아 내려는데
Have you brought the Veritaserum?
베리타세룸 가져왔나요?
I'm afraid you've used up
all my stores interrogating students.
일전에 초를 심문하면서
The last of it on Miss Chang.
제게 남아 있던 걸
다 쓰셨잖습니까
Unless you wish to poison him...
해리한테 독약을 먹일
And I assure you, I would have
the greatest sympathy if you did.
생각이 아니시라면
저로서는
- I cannot help you.
도와 드릴 수 없군요
He's got Padfoot.
패드풋을 잡아갔어요!
He's got Padfoot at the place
where it's hidden.
그게 숨겨진 장소로
데려갔다구요
Padfoot? What is Padfoot?
Where what is hidden?
패드풋이 뭐죠?
What is he talking about, Snape?
무슨 소리예요?
No idea.
모르겠군요
Very well.
좋아
You give me no choice, Potter.
그럼 어쩔 수 없지
As this is an issue
of Ministry security...
마법부 안전이 걸린
문제니만큼
...you leave me with...
입을 열게 하려면
...no alternative.
크루시아투스 저주를
The Cruciatus Curse
ought to loosen your tongue.
쓸 수밖에!
That's illegal.
그건 불법이에요!
What Cornelius doesn't know
won't hurt him.
장관님만 모르시면
문제 될 게 없지
Tell her, Harry!
말씀드려!
Tell me what?
뭘?
Well, if you won't tell her where it is...
네가 말 않겠다면
...I will.
내가 할 거야
Where what is?
뭘 말이지?
Dumbledore's secret weapon.
덤블도어의 비밀 무기요
How much further?
아직 멀었어?
Not far.
다 왔어요
It had to be somewhere
students wouldn't find it accidentally.
학생들 눈에 안 띄는 곳에
숨겨 뒀어요
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
Improvising.
임기응변!
Well?
그 무기…
Where is this weapon?
어딨지?
There isn't one, is there?
무기는 없는 거지?
You were trying to trick me.
날 속였어
You know...
난 정말
...I really hate children.
애들이 싫어!
You have no business here, centaur.
This is a Ministry matter.
너희는 끼어들지 마라
이건 마법부의 일이다
Lower your weapons.
무기를 내려놔
I warn you, under the law, as
creatures of near-human intelligence...
경고한다, 인간과 비슷한
지능을 가진 생물은…
Protego.
프로테고!
How dare you?
감히!
Filthy half-breed.
역겨운 잡종들!
Incarcerous.
인카서러스!
Please. Please stop it. Please.
제발 그만하세요!
제발요!
Now, enough. I will have order.
그만! 전부 가만있어!
You filthy animal.
더러운 짐승!
Do you know who I am?
내가 누군지 알고
이러는 거야?
Leave him alone. It's not his fault.
그롭 잘못이 아녜요!
No, he doesn't understand.
못 알아들어요!
Potter, do something.
Tell them I mean no harm.
해칠 생각 없었다고
말해 줘, 포터!
I'm sorry, professor.
죄송해요
But I must not tell lies.
거짓말 않겠다 맹세한걸요
What are you doing?
무슨 짓이야?
I am Senior Undersecretary
Dolores Jane Umbridge.
난 마법부 차관이야!
Let me go!
놔줘!
Thank you, Grawp.
고마워, 그롭
Hermione. Hermione, Sirius.
시리우스한테 가야 돼!
- How'd you get away?
- Puking Pastilles. It wasn't pretty.
- 어떻게 도망쳤어?
- 구역질 사탕 썼지
Told them I was hungry,
wanted some sweets.
배고프다고
사탕 달랬더니
They told me to bugger off
and ate the lot themselves.
웃기지 말라며
지들이 먹었어
That was clever, Ron.
머리 좀 썼는걸?
- Has been known to happen.
- It was brilliant.
- 가끔 써
- 기발했다구!
So how are we getting to London?
런던엔 어떻게 가지?
Look, it's not that I don't appreciate
everything you've done, all of you...
그동안 도와준 건
고맙지만
...but I've got you
into enough trouble as it is.
이제 그만 빠져
Dumbledore's Army's supposed to be
about doing something real.
덤블도어 군대
만든 이유 잊었어?
Or was that all just words to you?
말뿐이었던 거야?
Maybe you don't have to do this
all by yourself, mate.
넌 혼자가 아냐, 해리
So how are we going to get to London?
런던엔 어떻게 가지?
We fly, of course.
어떻게 가긴, 날아가야지!
Department of Mysteries.
미스터리 부서입니다
This is it.
여기야
Ninety-two. Ninety-three.
92, 93
Ninety-four.
Ninety-five.
- He should be here.
- Harry.
- 시리우스는 분명히 여어
- 해리
It's got your name on it.
네 이름이 적혔어
The one with the power
to vanquish the Dark Lord approaches.
어둠의 마왕을 물리칠
힘을 가진 자가 온다
And the Dark Lord
shall mark him as his equal...
허나, 어둠의 마왕은
...but he shall have power
the Dark Lord knows not.
그가 가진 힘을
알지 못한다
For neither can live
while the other survives.
한 사람만 살고
다른 한 사람은 죽는다
Harry.
해리!
Where's Sirius?
시리우스 어딨죠?
You know, you really should learn
to tell the difference between dreams...
꿈과 현실을
구별하는 법부터
...and reality.
배워야겠구나
You saw only what the Dark Lord
wanted you to see.
넌 어둠의 마왕께서
의도하신 것만 본 거야
Now, hand me the prophecy.
예언을 내놔
If you do anything to us, I'll break it.
우릴 건드렸다간
부술 거예요
He knows how to play.
어린 놈 배짱이
대단한걸
Itty, bitty baby.
아직 젖비린내도
가시질 않았는데
Potter.
포터!
Bellatrix Lestrange.
벨라트릭스 레스트랭
Neville Longbottom, is it?
How's Mum and Dad?
네빌 롱바텀이지?
엄마 아빤 잘 계셔?
Better, now they're
about to be avenged.
부모님 대신 복수하겠어!
Now, let's everybody
just calm down...
모두 일단 진정하자구
...shall we?
좋지?
All we want is that prophecy.
예언만 넘기면
곱게 가 주겠어
Why did Voldemort
need me to come and get this?
왜 볼드모트가
날 유인한 거지?
You dare speak his name?
감히 그분 이름을?
You filthy half-blood!
이 역겨운 잡종!
It's all right.
He's just a curious lad, aren't you?
괜찮아, 어린 마음에
궁금하겠지
Prophecies can only be retrieved
by those about whom they are made.
예언은 해당 당사자만
가져갈 수가 있거든
Which is lucky for you, really.
너한텐 행운인 거지
Haven't you always wondered...
안 궁금했나?
...the reason for the connection
between you and the Dark Lord?
너와 그분의 생각이
통한 이유가 뭔지?
Why he was unable to kill you...
왜 그분이 갓난아기인 널
...when you were just an infant?
죽이지 못했었는지?
Don't you want to know
the secret of your scar?
이마 흉터가 어떻게
생긴 건지 안 궁금해?
All the answers are there, Potter,
in your hand.
그 모든 해답들이
네 손에 들려 있다
All you have to do...
그걸 나한테
...is give it to me.
넘겨주면 돼
Then I can show you everything.
그럼 모든 궁금증을
다 풀어 줄게
I've waited 14 years.
14년을 기다렸어
I know.
알아
I guess I can wait a little longer.
Now. Stupefy.
더 기다릴 수 있어
지금이야! 스투페파이!
Stupefy.
Levicorpus.
레비코푸스!
Petrificus Totalus.
페트리피쿠스 토탈루스!
Well done, Neville.
잘했어, 네빌
Stupefy.
- Stupefy.
- 스투페파이!
Stupefy.
스투페파이!
Reducto.
리덕토!
Get back to the door.
문으로 가!
Department of Mysteries.
They got that bit right, didn't they?
정말 이름처럼
미스터리한 곳이지?
The voices.
목소리가 들려
Can you tell what they're saying?
뭐라는 거지?
There aren't any voices, Harry.
아무 소리 안 들려
Let's get out of here.
여길 나가자
I hear them too.
나도 들려
Harry, it's just an empty archway.
그냥 뻥 뚫린 아치야
Please, Harry.
제발, 해리
Get behind me.
내 뒤로 와!
Did you actually believe...
궁금해서 묻는 건데
...or were you truly naive enough
to think...
설마 네놈들 같은
꼬맹이들이
...that children stood a chance
against us?
우릴 이길 수 있다고
생각하진 않았겠지?
I'll make this simple for you, Potter.
쉽게 끝낼 수 있다, 포터
Give me the prophecy now...
나한테 예언을 넘겨
...or watch your friends die.
아님 친구들 죽는 걸
보게 될 거야
Don't give it to him, Harry.
주면 안 돼!
Get away from my godson.
해리한테서 떨어져!
Now, listen to me.
Take the others and get out of here.
친구들 데리고
여길 빠져나가
What? No, I'm staying with you.
아뇨! 아저씨랑 있을래요
You've done beautifully.
지금까지 잘해 줬다
Now, let me take it from here.
이젠 나한테 맡겨
Black.
블랙!
Expelliarmus!
엑스펠리아르무스!
Nice one, James.
잘했다, 제임스!
Avada Kedavra.
아바다 케다브라!
No. No.
I killed Sirius Black.
내가 시리우스를 죽였다!
- You coming to get me?
- Crucio.
- 어쩔 거지?
- 크루시오!
You've got to mean it, Harry.
주문에 진심으로
저주를 담아야지
She killed him. She deserves it.
시리우스를 죽였잖아
죽어 마땅해
You know the spell, Harry.
주문을 알잖아
해리
Do it.
죽여!
So weak.
나약한 놈
It was foolish of you
to come here tonight, Tom.
여기 나타나다니
어리석군, 톰
The Aurors are on their way.
오러들이 오고 있다
By which time I shall be gone,
and you...
그들이 오면
난 없을 테고, 자넨
...shall be dead.
죽어 있겠지
You've lost, old man.
네가 졌어, 늙은이
Harry.
해리
So weak.
나약한 놈
So vulnerable.
약해 빠졌어
Look at me.
날 봐라
Harry, it isn't how you are alike.
중요한 건
얼마나 닮았는지가 아니다
It's how you are not.
어떻게 다른가지
Harry?
해리
You're the weak one...
나약한 건 당신이야
...and you'll never know
love or friendship.
사랑이나 우정이 뭔지
영원히 모르겠지
And I feel sorry for you.
난 당신이 불쌍해
You're a fool, Harry Potter.
정말 어리석군, 해리 포터
And you will lose everything.
넌 모든 걸 잃게 될 거다
He's back.
그가 돌아왔어!
덤블도어와 포터
명예를 회복하다
퍼지 장관 사임?
엄브릿지 수사를 중단시키다
이름을 불러서는 안 될
그 사람이 돌아오다
덤블도어 호그와트
교장으로 복직
I know how you feel, Harry.
네 기분 안다
No, you don't.
모르실 거예요
It's my fault.
제 잘못이에요
No, the fault is mine.
아니, 내 잘못이다
I knew it was only a matter of time...
볼드모트가 네 마음속에
...before Voldemort made the connection
between you.
들어갈 거란 걸 알았지만
I thought by distancing myself from you,
as I have done all year...
내가 네 곁에서
떨어져 있으면
...he'd be less tempted, and therefore
you might be more protected.
널 그냥
내버려 둘 줄 알았다
The prophecy said:
예언이 말하길
"Neither one can live
while the other one survives."
"한 사람만 살고
다른 한 사람은 죽는다"
It means one of us is gonna
have to kill the other, in the end.
결국 우리 둘 중 하난
죽어야 끝나요
Yes.
그래
Why didn't you tell me?
왜 말 안 하셨죠?
For the same reason
you tried to save Sirius.
네가 시리우스를
구하려 했던 것과
The same reason your friends saved you.
친구들이 널 구해 준
이유와 같지
After all these years,
after all you've suffered...
지난 몇 년간
큰 고통을 겪었잖니
...I didn't want to cause you
any more pain.
또 다른 고통을
안겨 주긴 싫었다
I cared too much about you.
널 그만큼 아끼니까
How come you're not at the feast?
왜 파티에 안 갔어?
Lost all my possessions. Apparently
people have been hiding them.
내 물건들이 없어졌어
애들이 숨겼나 봐
That's awful.
너무했다
Oh, it's all good fun.
장난인걸 뭐
But as it's the last night,
I really do need them back.
그치만 마지막 날이니
전부 찾아야 돼
Do you want any help finding them?
찾는 거 도와줄까?
I'm sorry about your godfather, Harry.
시리우스 일은 정말 안 됐어
Are you sure you don't want
any help looking?
정말 안 도와줘도 돼?
That's all right.
괜찮아
Anyway, my mum always said...
엄마가 늘 그러셨어
...the things we lose have a way
of coming back to us in the end.
잃어버린 물건은 결국
그 주인한테 돌아온다
If not always in the way we expect.
때론 우리가
예상 못 한 방식으로
Think I'll just go have some pudding.
난 푸딩 먹으러 갈래
I've been thinking about something
Dumbledore said to me.
덤블도어가 한 말,
곰곰이 생각해 봤어
What's that?
뭐랬는데?
That even though
we've got a fight ahead of us...
힘든 싸움이겠지만
우리한텐
...we've got one thing
that Voldemort doesn't have.
볼드모트한테
없는 게 있댔어
Yeah?
그게 뭔데?
Something worth fighting for.
싸워 지켜야 할
소중한 친구들!